Guide to the J. Walter Thompson Company. Bill Lane Papers, 1967-1978
The John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
J. Walter Thompson Company. Bill Lane papers 1967-1978
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library, Duke University
J. Walter Thompson Company.
2.0 Linear Feet 1,000 Items
Established in 1864, the J. Walter Thompson Company (JWT) is one of the oldest and largest enduring advertising agencies in the United States. William M. Bill Lane was a Creative Director and Executive at several JWT offices.
Collection spans the years 1967-1978 and includes account planning documents, creative briefs, correspondence and printed materials that primarily document the early years of Lane's career at JWT. The bulk of materials relate to Kodak campaigns in print, radio and television media. Acquired as part of the John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48-hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
The J. Walter Thompson Company Bill Lane Papers were received by the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library as a gift in 1996.
Biographical Note
Chronology List
1946 Born, San Francisco, Calif.
1967 BA, Journalism/Advertising, University of Washington
1967-1969 JWT New York Office; copywriter in Forward Planning Creative Group
1969-1971 U.S. Army, Public Informationn Specialist
1971 Return to JWT
1973-1974 JWT New York Office, Copy Group Head, Assistant Creative Director on Kodak account
1975 JWT, promoted to Vice President
1977 JWT, promoted to Senior Vice President
1977 RIAA Gold Record for Times of Your Life, lyrics by Bill Lane for Kodak campaign, subsequently recorded by Paul Anka
1979 JWT Detroit Office, Creative Director on Ford account
1982 JWT Detroit Office, Executive Creative Director
1983 JWT, promoted to Executive Vice President, named to Board of Directors
1984 JWT San Francisco Office, Executive Creative Director
1988 JWT New York Office, Co-Executive Creative Director
1990 JWT West, Executive Vice President
1993 Lane Gottlieb Advertising, partner
1997 Lane Gottlieb merged with McCaffery & Ratner to form McCaffery Ratner Gottlieb & Lane; Lane named Creative Director
Collection Overview
Collection spans the years 1967-1978 and includes account planning documents, creative briefs, correspondence and printed materials that primarily document the early years of Lane's career at JWT. The bulk of materials relate to Kodak campaigns in print, radio and television media.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Lane, William M.
J. Walter Thompson Company
Eastman Kodak Company
Advertising
Advertising -- United States
Advertising -- United States -- History
Advertising agencies
Advertising agencies -- United States
Advertising agencies -- United States -- History
Advertising executives
Radio advertising
Radio advertising -- 1970-1980
Television advertising
John W. Hartman Center for Sales, Advertising & Marketing History
Related Material
Related materials may be found in the following Hartman Center collections:
J. Walter Thompson Company Account Files
J. Walter Thompson Company Domestic Advertisements
J. Walter Thompson Company Granger Tripp Papers
Wayne P. Ellis Collection of Kodakiana
Detailed Description of Collection
- General Files, 1975-1976
  - Telephone records, 1975-1976 (Box 1)
- Kodak Account Files, 1967-1978
  - Born and Bred campaign, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Campaigns, 1971-1974
  - Christmas, 1974
  - Christmas and Spring advertising, 1977-1978
  - JWT Professional Forum presentation, 1971-1972
  - Media plan, 1972 (Box 2)
  - Memoranda, 1973-1977
  - Miscellaneous scripts, 1975
  - P23/Ektasound, 1972-1973
  - P23/Ektasound, 1972-1973 (Box 3)
  - P23/Ektasound international launch, 1973
  - P30/Instamatic, 1971-1972
  - P130/Instant cameras, 1975-1976
  - P158/Ektra, 1977
  - Print, 1973-1977
  - Print, 1973-1977 (Box 4)
  - Print/broadcast, 1971-1972
  - Print, major consumer campaigns, 1971
  - Quilt of My Years film concept, 1972
  - Radio, 1974-1975
  - Radio/Television, 1973, 1977
  - Television, 1967-1975
  - Television, 1967-1975 (Box 5)
  - Time of Your Life film/song, 1973-1974
  - Time of Your Life radio, 1975